export const PICTUREMAKINGA2022 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Persons who have interest and appreciate art are",
A: "connoisseurs.",
B: "curators.",
C: "experts.",
D: "professionals.",
answer: "A. connoisseurs.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of these artists was a prominent sculptor in Ghana?",
A: "Amon Kotei",
B: "F. Martey",
C: "Kofi Setordzi",
D: "Vincent Kofi",
answer: "D. Vincent Kofi",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The material mostly used by the ancient Greeks for their sculpture is",
A: "alabaster.",
B: "granite.",
C: "marble.",
D: "sandstone.",
answer: "C. marble.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. An armature is put into a cement statue to",
A: "enhance it’s texture.",
B: "improve porosity.",
C: "increase it’s strength.",
D: "prevent warping.",
answer: "C. increase it’s strength.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Identify the material suitable for synthetic sculpture.",
A: "Bone",
B: "Hom",
C: "Wax",
D: "Wood",
answer: "B. Hom",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of these materials is organic?",
A: "Ivory",
B: "Leather",
C: "Plaster",
D: "Wood",
answer: "D. Wood",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The appropriate tool for cutting a 2.5 cm thick iron rod is",
A: "band saw.",
B: "hacksaw.",
C: "pliers.",
D: "snips.",
answer: "B. hacksaw.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The suitable material for coating a plaster cast is",
A: "cement.",
B: "putty.",
C: "shellac.",
D: "slip.",
answer: "C. shellac.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Heartwood is most suitable for carving because it is",
A: "durable.",
B: "elastic.",
C: "flexible.",
D: "spongy.",
answer: "A. durable.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. To save time in the execution of a sculpture, one needs to use",
A: "manual tools.",
B: "metal armatures.",
C: "preliminary designs.",
D: "soft materials.",
answer: "C. preliminary designs.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A usual appeal in a work of art is referred to as",
A: "balance.",
B: "emphasis.",
C: "movement.",
D: "proportion.",
answer: "B. emphasis.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. preliminary designing, a maquette",
A: "gives an estimate of production cost.",
B: "gives an overview of the finished work.",
C: "tests the creative skills of the sculptor.",
D: "tests the medium for the final work.",
answer: "B. gives an overview of the finished work.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. three-dimensional work compared to that of vo-dimensional has",
A: "area.",
B: "circumference.",
C: "diameter.",
D: "volume.",
answer: "D. volume.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of these materials needs extreme heat to work with?",
A: "Glass",
B: "Ivory",
C: "Stone",
D: "Wood",
answer: "A. Glass",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The two methods by which clay is cast are",
A: "kneading and pinching.",
B: "modelling and pressing.",
C: "punching and stamping.",
D: "pouring and pressing.",
answer: "D. pouring and pressing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The thickness of the wall of terracotta work is achieved by",
A: "kneading.",
B: "pinching.",
C: "punching.",
D: "scooping.",
answer: "D. scooping.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. kan brass weights are produced by",
A: "lost wax technique.",
B: "sand casting.",
C: "shell casting.",
D: "slip casting technique.",
answer: "A. lost wax technique.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. ssem blage ial with pre-existing forms where as in construction, forms are usually",
A: "altered.",
B: "bonded.",
C: "chased.",
D: "riveted.",
answer: "B. bonded.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Sculptors explain /i/ling-in as",
A: "mending cracks on a cast.",
B: "mending cracks in a mould.",
C: "pouring liquid materials into a mould.",
D: "sizing adry mould.",
answer: "C. pouring liquid materials into a mould.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Leather hard clay sculptures are usually decorated by",
A: "firing.",
B: "scorching.",
C: "texturing.",
D: "varnishing.",
answer: "C. texturing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following is a reason for finishing and decorating sculpture?",
A: "Adding value to it",
B: "Changing it’s design",
C: "Making it durable",
D: "Making it easy to handle",
answer: "A. Adding value to it",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Indicate the cause of pinholes in a POP cast from the following.",
A: "Escaped air bubbles",
B: "fast casting",
C: "Slow casting",
D: "Trapped air bubbles",
answer: "D. Trapped air bubbles",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Inthe modelling studio, the frog is useful for",
A: "cutting clay lumps.",
B: "incising clay.",
C: "removing air pockets.",
D: "stirring slip.",
answer: "C. removing air pockets.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Exhibitions are avenues for displaying and",
A: "admiring sculptures.",
B: "costing products.",
C: "pricing sculptures.",
D: "selling products.",
answer: "D. selling products.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following is an acceptable condition in a sculpture studio?",
A: "Sealing doors and windows",
B: "Using sun glasses",
C: "Wearing of nose masks",
D: "Wearing of slippers",
answer: "C. Wearing of nose masks",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Suitable materials in the environment are sustained by",
A: "buying cheap materials.",
B: "creating waste through usage.",
C: "replenishing.",
D: "stockpiling.",
answer: "C. replenishing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Invitations and brochures are very important considerations for",
A: "learming activities.",
B: "mounting an exhibition.",
C: "mounting a statue.",
D: "setting up an enterprise.",
answer: "B. mounting an exhibition.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Pictures of artworks are stored electronically",
A: "in photoshop.",
B: "on auto card,",
C: "on compact disk.",
D: "on the monitor.",
answer: "C. on compact disk.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Basic marketing strategies involve",
A: "appreciation and criticism.",
B: "exhibitions and fairs.",
C: "profit and loss.",
D: "security and risks.",
answer: "B. exhibitions and fairs.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following is required to set.up a sculpture industry?",
A: "Current savings account.",
B: "Fixed and variable cost.",
C: "Fixed and working capital.",
D: "Gross and net income.",
answer: "C. Fixed and working capital.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. One major reason for packaging sculpture is to prevent",
A: "damage.",
B: "exposure.",
C: "imitation.",
D: "theft.",
answer: "A. damage.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Determining the market nitche for a product helps in",
A: "assessing.",
B: "directing.",
C: "evaluating.",
D: "planning.",
answer: "B. directing.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Lettering is rendered in scllpture mainly by",
A: "burning.",
B: "carving.",
C: "casting.",
D: "throwing.",
answer: "B. carving.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Sculpture that incorporates motion is said to be",
A: "environmental.",
B: "glyptic.",
C: "kinetic.",
D: "repulsive.",
answer: "C. kinetic.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Patination is the process of",
A: "colouring sculpture to imitate bronze.",
B: "making designs on a cast.",
C: "polishing bronze statues.",
D: "removing impurities from a bronze cast.",
answer: "A. colouring sculpture to imitate bronze.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The application of wood-stain on wood carving",
A: "enhances the grain.",
B: "makes it water proof.",
C: "prevents warpage.",
D: "opens up the pores.",
answer: "A. enhances the grain.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The main reasson for the study of sculpture is to",
A: "be respected in the society.",
B: "care about tools and materials.",
C: "give form to ideas.",
D: "learn about techniques.",
answer: "C. give form to ideas.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. In the lost-wax process, unwanted projections on the cast are removed by",
A: "burnishing.",
B: "chasing.",
C: "polishing.",
D: "sand blasting.",
answer: "B. chasing.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The focus of a three-dimensional art is on",
A: "colour and texture.",
B: "mass and space,",
C: "space and colour.",
D: "texture and mass.",
answer: "B. mass and space,",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Select the most durable material for outdoor sculpture.",
A: "Bone",
B: "Soapstone",
C: "Terra cotta",
D: "Wood",
answer: "B. Soapstone",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]